<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    
    <string name="what_is_a_spell">
        A spell is a discrete magical effect, a single shaping
        of the magical energies that suffuse the multiverse
        into a specific, limited expression. In casting a spell,
        a character carefully plucks at the invisible strands of
        raw magic suffusing the world, pins them in place in a
        particular pattern, sets them vibrating in a specific way,
        and then releases them to unleash the desired effect - in
        most cases, all in the span of seconds.
        Spells can be versatile tools, weapons, or protective
        wards. They can deal damage or undo it, impose or
        remove conditions, drain life energy
        away, and restore life to the dead.
        \n\tUncounted thousands of spells have been created
        over the course of the multiverse\'s history, and many of
        them are long forgotten. Some might yet lie recorded in
        crumbling spellbooks hidden in ancient ruins or trapped
        in the minds of dead gods. Or they might someday be
        reinvented by a character who has amassed enough
        power and wisdom to do so.
    </string>

    <string name="spell_level_info">
        Every spell has a level from 0 to 9. A spell\'s level is a
        general indicator of how powerful it is, with the lowly
        (but still impressive) <i>magic missile</i> at 1st level and
        the earth-shaking <i>wish</i> at 9th. Cantrips - simple
        but powerful spells that characters can cast almost by rote -
        are level 0. The higher a spell\'s level, the higher level a
        spellcaster must be to use that spell.
        \n\tSpell level and character level don\'t correspond
        directly. Typically, a character has to be at least 17th
        level, not 9th level, to cast a 9th-level spell.
    </string>

    <string name="known_and_prepared_spells">
        Before a spellcaster can use a spell, he or she must
        have the spell firmly fixed in mind, or must have access
        to the spell in a magic item. Members of a few classes,
        including bards and sorcerers, have a limited list of
        spells they know that are always fixed in mind. The
        same thing is true of many magic-using monsters. Other
        spellcasters, such as clerics and wizards, undergo a
        process of preparing spells. This process varies for
        different classes, as detailed in their descriptions.\n
        \tIn every case, the number of spells a caster can
        have fixed in mind at any given time depends on the
        character\'s level.
    </string>
    
    <string name="spell_slots_info">
        Regardless of how many spells a caster knows or
        prepares, he or she can cast only a limited number of
        spells before resting. Manipulating the fabric of magic
        and channeling its energy into even a simple spell is
        physically and mentally taxing, and higher-level spells
        are even more so. Thus, each spellcasting class\'s
        description (except that of the warlock) includes a table
        showing how many spell slots of each spell level a
        character can use at each character level. For example,
        the 3rd-level wizard Umara has four 1st-level spell slots
        and two 2nd-level slots.
        \n\tWhen a character casts a spell, he or she expends
        a slot of that spell\'s level or higher, effectively "filling"
        a slot with the spell. You can think of a spell slot as a
        groove of a certain size - small for a 1st-level slot, larger
        for a spell of higher level. A 1st-level spell fits into a slot
        of any size, but a 9th-level spell fits only in a 9th-level
        slot. So when Umara casts magic missile, a 1st-level
        spell, she spends one of her four 1st-level slots and has
        three remaining.
        \n\tFinishing a long rest restores any expended spell slots
        (see chapter 8 for the rules on resting).
        \n\tSome characters and monsters have special abilities
        that let them cast spells without using spell slots. For
        example, a monk who follows the Way of the Four
        Elements, a warlock who chooses certain eldritch
        invocations, and a pit fiend from the Nine Hells can all
        cast spells in such a way.
        \n\n<b>CASTING A SPELL AT A HIGHER LEVEL</b>
        \n\tWhen a spellcaster casts a spell using a slot that is of a
        higher level than the spell, the spell assumes the higher
        level for that casting. For instance, if Umara casts <i>magic
        missile</i> using one of her 2nd-level slots, that <i>magic
        missile</i> is 2nd level. Effectively, the spell expands to fill
        the slot it is put into.
        \tSome spells, such as <i>magic missile</i> and <i>cure wounds</i>,
        have more powerful effects when cast at a higher level,
        as detailed in a spell\'s description.
    </string>

    <string name="cantrips">
        A cantrip is a spell that can be cast at will, without
        using a spell slot and without being prepared in
        advance. Repeated practice has fixed the spell in the
        caster\'s mind and infused the caster with the magic
        needed to produce the effect over and over. A cantrip\'s
        spell level is 0.
    </string>

    <string name="rituals">
        Certain spells have a special tag: ritual. Such a spell
        can be cast following the normal rules for spellcasting,
        or the spell can be cast as a ritual. The ritual version of
        a spell takes 10 minutes longer to cast than normal.
        It also doesn\'t expend a spell slot, which means the
        ritual version of a spell can\'t be cast at a higher level.
        \n\tTo cast a spell as a ritual, a spellcaster must have a
        feature that grants the ability to do so. The cleric and the
        druid, for example, have such a feature. The caster must
        also have the spell prepared or on his or her list of spells
        known, unless the character\'s ritual feature specifies
        otherwise, as the wizard\'s does.
    </string>

    <string name="casting_time_info">
        Most spells require a single action to cast, but some
        spells require a bonus action, a reaction, or much more
        time to cast.
        \n\n<b>BONUS ACTION</b>
        \nA spell cast with a bonus action is especially swift. You
        must use a bonus action on your turn to cast the spell,
        provided that you haven\'t already taken a bonus action
        this turn. You can\'t cast another spell during the same
        turn, except for a cantrip with a casting time of 1 action.
        \n\n<b>REACTIONS</b>
        \nSome spells can be cast as reactions. These spells
        take a fraction of a second to bring about and are cast
        in response to some event. If a spell can be cast as a
        reaction, the spell description tells you exactly when
        you can do so.
        \n\n<b>LONGER CASTING TIMES</b>
        \nCertain spells (including spells cast as rituals) require
        more time to cast: minutes or even hours. When you
        cast a spell with a casting time longer than a single
        action or reaction, you must spend your action each
        turn casting the spell, and you must maintain your
        concentration while you do so (see "Concentration"
        below). If your concentration is broken, the spell fails,
        but you don\'t expend a spell slot. If you want to try
        casting the spell again, you must start over.
    </string>

    <string name="range_info">
        The target of a spell must be within the spell\'s range.
        For a spell like <i>magic missile</i>, the target is a creature.
        For a spell like <i>fireball</i>, the target is the point in space
        where the ball of fire erupts.
        \n\tMost spells have ranges expressed in feet. Some
        spells can target only a creature (including you) that you
        touch. Other spells. such as the <i>shield</i> spell, affect only
        you. These spells have a range of self.
        \n\tSpells that create cones or lines of effect that originate
        from you also have a range of self, indicating that the
        origin point of the spell\'s effect must be you (see \"Areas
        of Effect\").
        \n\tOnce a spell is cast, its effects aren\'t limited by its
        range, unless the spell\'s description says otherwise.
    </string>

    <string name="components_info">
        A spell\'s components are the physical requirements you
        must meet in order to cast it. Each spell\'s description
        indicates whether it requires verbal (V), somatic (S),
        material (M), or royalty (R) components. If you can\'t provide one
        or more of a spell\'s components, you are unable to
        cast the spell.
        \n\n<b>VERBAL (V)</b>
        \nMost spells require the chanting of mystic words. The
        words themselves aren\'t the source of the spell\'s power;
        rather, the particular combination of sounds, with
        specific pitch and resonance, sets the threads of magic
        in motion. Thus, a character who is gagged or in an area
        of silence, such as one created by the <i>silence</i> spell, can\'t
        cast a spell with a verbal component.
        \n\n<b>SOMATIC (S)</b>
        \nSpellcasting gestures might include a forceful
        gesticulation or an intricate set of gestures. If a spell
        requires a somatic component, the caster must have free
        use of at least one hand to perform these gestures.
        \n\n<b>MATERIAL (M)</b>
        \nCasting some spells requires particular objects,
        specified in parentheses in the component entry.
        \nA character can use a <b>component pouch</b> or a
        <b>spellcasting focus</b> (found in chapter 5) in place of
        the components specified for a spell. But if a cost is
        indicated for a component, a character must have that
        specific component before he or she can cast the spell.
        \n\tIf a spell states that a material component is
        consumed by the spell, the caster must provide this
        component for each casting of the spell.
        \n\tA spellcaster must have a hand free to access these
        components, but it can be the same hand that he or she
        uses to perform somatic components.
        \n\n<b>ROYALTY (R)</b>
        \nJim Darkmagic\'s unique brand of spellcasting mixes arcane
        expertise with a particular kind of pecuniary fervor. New
        spells originally developed by Jim spawned a new type of spell
        component, which has since spread to other spells created by
        employees and franchisees of Acquisitions Incorporated:
        the royalty component.
        \nTo cast a spell that employs a royalty component (including
        using a spell scroll or other magic item that stores such a
        spell), a caster must have sufficient funds on their person.
        The cost of the casting is set by the caster who creates the
        spell, but is typically 1 gp per spell slot level. When the spell
        is cast, the royalty is magically transported to a coffer or other
        object designated by the creating spellcaster. This payment is
        made whether the caster using the spell is aware of the royalty
        component or not. If the caster does not have sufficient funds,
        the spell is not lost but it cannot be cast.
        \nThough many casters have tried to circumvent the royalty component,
        none have ever fully succeeded. However, it is said that a character
        can attempt a DC 15 Intelligence (Arcana) check while casting a spell
        with a royalty component. With a successful check, the payment is taken
        from a random creature within 10 feet of the caster, without that
        creature\'s knowledge.
    </string>

    <string name="duration_info">
        A spell\'s duration is the length of time the spell persists.
        A duration can be expressed in rounds, minutes, hours,
        or even years. Some spells specify that their effects last
        until the spells are dispelled or destroyed.
        \n\n<b>INSTANTANEOUS</b>
        \nMany spells are instantaneous. The spell harms,
        heals, creates, or alters a creature or an object in a way
        that can\'t be dispelled, because its magic exists only
        for an instant.
        \n\n<b>CONCENTRATION</b>
        \nSome spells require you to maintain concentration
        in order to keep their magic active. If you lose
        concentration, such a spell ends.
        \n\tIf a spell must be maintained with concentration,
        that fact appears in its Duration entry, and the spell
        specifies how long you can concentrate on it. You can
        end concentration at any time (no action required).
        \n\tNormal activity, such as moving and attacking, doesn\'t
        interfere with concentration. The following factors can
        break concentration:
        \n\n<b>&#8226; Casting another spell that requires concentration.</b>
        You lose concentration on a spell if you cast another
        spell that requires concentration. You can\'t concentrate
        on two spells at once.
        \n<b>&#8226; Taking damage.</b> Whenever you take damage while
        you are concentrating on a spell, you must make a
        Constitution saving throw to maintain your concentration.
        The DC equals 10 or half the damage you take,
        whichever number is higher. If you take damage from
        multiple sources, such as an arrow and a dragon\'s
        breath, you make a separate saving throw for each
        source of damage.
        \n<b>&#8226; Being incapacitated or killed.</b> You lose concentration
        on a spell if you are incapacitated or if you die.
        \n\n\tThe DM might also decide that certain environmental
        phenomena, such as a wave crashing over you while
        you\'re on a storm-tossed ship, require you to succeed
        on a DC 10 Constitution saving throw to maintain
        concentration on a spell.
    </string>

    <string name="targets">
        A typical spell requires you to pick one or more targets
        to be affected by the spell\'s magic. A spell\'s description
        tells you whether the spell targets creatures, objects, or
        a point of origin for an area of effect (described below).
        \n\tUnless a spell has a perceptible effect, a creature
        might not know it was targeted by a spell at all. An effect
        like crackling lightning is obvious, but a more subtle
        effect, such as an attempt to read a creature\'s thoughts,
        typically goes unnoticed, unless a spell says otherwise.
        \n\n<b>A CLEAR PATH TO THE TARGET</b>
        \nTo target something, you must have a clear path to it,
        so it can\'t be behind total cover.
        \n\tIf you place an area of effect at a point that you can\'t
        see and an obstruction. such as a wall, is between you
        and that point, the point of origin comes into being on
        the near side of that obstruction.
        \n\n<b>TARGETING YOURSELF</b>
        \nIf a spell targets a creature of your choice, you can
        choose yourself, unless the creature must be hostile or
        specifically a creature other than you. lf you are in the
        area of effect of a spell you cast, you can target yourself.
    </string>

    <string name="areas_of_effect">
        Spells such as <i>burning hands</i> and <i>cone of cold</i> cover an
        area, allowing them to affect multiple creatures at once.
        \n\tA spell\'s description specifies its area af effect,
        which typically has ane of five different shapes: cone,
        cube, cylinder, line, or sphere. Every area of effect has
        a <b>point of origin</b>, a location from which the spell\'s
        energy erupts. The roles for each shape specify how you position
        its point of origin. Typically, a point of origin is a point in space, but
        some spells have an area whose origin is a creature or an object.
        \n\tA spell\'s effect expands in straight lines from the point
        of origin. If no unblocked straight line extends from the
        point of origin to a location within the area of effect, that
        location isn\'t included in the spell\'s area. To block one of
        these imaginary lines, an obstruction must provide total
        cover.
        \n\n<b>CONE</b>
        \nA cone extends in a direction you choose from its point
        of origin. A cone\'s width at a given point along its length
        is equal to that point\'s distance from the point of origin.
        A cone\'s area of effect specifies its maximum length.
        \n\tA cone\'s point of origin is not included in the cone\'s
        area of effect, unless you decide otherwise.
        \n\n<b>CUBE</b>
        \nYou select a cube\'s point of origin, which lies anywhere
        on a face of the cubic effect. The cube\'s size is expressed
        as the length of each side.
        \n\tA cube\'s point of origin is not included in the cube\'s
        area of effect, unless you decide otherwise.
        \n\n<b>CYLINDER</b>
        \nA cylinder\'s point of origin is the center of a circle of a
        particular radius, as given in the spell description. The
        circle must either be on the ground or at the height of
        the spell effect. The energy in a cylinder expands in
        straight lines from the point of origin to the perimeter of
        the circle, forming the base of the cylinder. The spell\'s
        effect then shoots up from the base or down from the
        top, to a distance equal to the height of the cylinder.
        \n\tA cylinder\'s point of origin is included in the cylinder\'s
        area of effect.
        \n\n<b>LINE</b>
        \nA line extends from its point of origin in a straight path
        up to its length and covers an area defined by its width.
        \n\tA line\'s point of origin is not included in the line\'s area
        of effect, unless you decide otherwise.
        \n\n<b>SPHERE</b>
        \nYou select a sphere\'s point of origin, and the sphere
        extends outward from that point. The sphere\'s
        size is expressed as a radius in feet that extends
        from the point.
        \n\tA sphere\'s point of origin is included in the sphere\'s
        area of effect.
    </string>

    <string name="saving_throws">
        Many spells specify that a target can make a saving
        throw to avoid some or all of a spell\'s effects. The spell
        specifies the ability that the target uses for the save and
        what happens on a success or failure.
        \n\tThe DC to resist one of your spells equals 8 + your
        spellcasting ability modifier + your proficiency bonus +
        any special modifiers.
    </string>

    <string name="attack_rolls">
        Some spells require the caster to make an attack roll
        to determine whether the spell effect hits the intended
        target. Your attack bonus with a spell attack equals your
        spellcasting ability modifier + your proficiency bonus.
        \n\tMost spells that require attack rolls involve ranged
        attacks. Remember that you have disadvantage
        on a ranged attack roll if you are within 5 feet of a hostile
        creature that can see you and that isn\'t incapacitated.
    </string>

    <string name="combining_magical_effects">
        The effects of different spells add together while
        the durations of those spells overlap. The effects of
        the same spell cast multiple times don\'t combine,
        however. Instead, the most potent effect - such as the
        highest bonus - from those castings applies while their durations overlap.
        \n\tFor example, if two clerics cast bless on the same
        target, that character gains the spell\'s benefit only
        once; he or she doesn\'t get to roll two bonus dice.
    </string>

    <string name="casting_in_armor">
        Because of the mental focus and precise gestures required for spellcasting, you must
        be proficient with the armor you are wearing to cast a spell. You are otherwise too distracted
        and physically hampered by your armor for spellcasting.
    </string>

    <string name="the_schools_of_magic">
        Academies of magic group spells into eight categories called
        schools of magic. Scholars, particularly wizards, apply these
        categories to all spells, believing that all magic functions in
        essentially the same way, whether it derives from rigorous
        study or is bestowed by a deity.
        \n\tThe schools of magic help describe spells; they have no
        rules of their own, although some rules refer to the schools.
        \n<b>Abjuration</b> spells are protective in nature, though some
        of them have aggressive uses. They create magical barriers,
        negate harmful effects, harm trespassers, or banish creatures
        to other planes of existence.
        \n<b>Conjuration</b> spells involve the transportation of objects
        and creatures from one location to another. Some spells
        summon creatures or objects to the caster\'s side, whereas
        others allow the caster to teleport to another location. Some
        conjurations create objects or effects out of nothing.
        \n<b>Divination</b> spells reveal information, whether in the form of
        secrets long forgotten, glimpses of the future, the locations
        of hidden things, the truth behind illusions, or visions of
        distant people or places.
        \n<b>Enchantment</b> spells affect the minds of others, influencing
        or controlling their behavior. Such spells can make enemies
        see the caster as a friend, force creatures to take a course of
        action, or even control another creature like a puppet.
        \n<b>Evocation</b> spells manipulate magical energy to produce a
        desired effect. Some call up blasts of fire or lightning. Others
        channel positive energy to heal wounds.
        \n<b>Illusion</b> spells deceive the senses or minds of others. They
        cause people to see things that are not there, to miss things
        that are there, to hear phantom noises, or to remember
        things that never happened. Some illusions create phantom
        images that any creature can see, but the most insidious
        illusions plant an image directly in the mind of a creature.
        \n<b>Necromancy</b> spells manipulate the energies of life and
        death. Such spells can grant an extra reserve of life force,
        drain the life energy from another creature, create the
        undead, or even bring the dead back to life.
        Creating the undead through the use of necromancy spells
        such as animate dead is not a good act, and only evil casters
        use such spells frequently.
        \n<b>Transmutation</b> spells change the properties of a creature,
        object, or environment. They might turn an enemy into a
        harmless creature. bolster the strength of an ally, make an
        object move at the caster\'s command, or enhance a creature\'s
        innate healing abilities to rapidly recover from injury.
    </string>

    <string name="the_weave_of_magic">
        The worlds within the D&amp;D multiverse are magical places.
        All existence is suffused with magical power, and potential
        energy lies untapped in every rock, stream, and living
        creature, and even in the air itself. Raw magic is the stuff of
        creation, the mute and mindless will of existence, permeating
        every bit of matter and present in every manifestation of
        energy throughout the multiverse.
        \n\tMortals can\'t directly shape this raw magic. Instead, they
        make use of a fabric of magic, a kind of interface between
        the will of a spellcaster and the stuff of raw magic. The
        spellcasters of the Forgotten Realms call it the Weave and
        recognize its essence as the goddess Mystra, but casters
        have varied ways of naming and visualizing this interface. Say
        any name, without the Weave, raw magic is locked away and
        inaccessible; the most powerful archmage can\'t light a candle
        with magic in an area where the Weave has been torn. But
        surrounded by the Weave, a spellcaster can shape lightning
        to blast foes, transport hundreds of miles in the blink of an
        eye, or even reverse death itself.
        \n\tAll magic depends on the Weave, though different kinds
        of magic access it in a variety of ways. The spells of wizards,
        warlocks, sorcerers, and bards are commonly called <b>arcane
        magic</b>. These spells rely on an understanding - learned
        or intuitive - of the workings of the Weave. The caster plucks
        directly at the strands of the Weave to create the desired
        effect. Eldritch knights and arcane tricksters also use arcane
        magic. the spells of derics, druids, paladins, and rangers are
        called <b>divine magic</b>. These spellcasters\' access to the Weave
        is mediated by divine power - gods, the divine forces of
        nature, or the sacred weight of a paladin\'s oath.
        \n\tWhenever a magic effect is created, the threads of the
        Weave intertwine, twist, and fold to make the effect possible.
        When characters use divination spells such as <i>detect magic</i> or
        <i>identify</i>, they glimpse the Weave. A spell such as <i>dispel magic</i>
        smooths the Weave. Spells such as <i>antimagic field</i> rearrange
        the Weave so that magic flows around, rather than through,
        the area affected by the spell. And in places where the Weave
        is damaged or torn, magic works in unpredictable ways - or
        not at all.
    </string>

    <string name="artificer_spellcasting_info">
        <b>MAGICAL TINKERING</b>
        \n<i>1st-level artificer feature</i>
        \nYou\'ve learned how to invest a spark of magic into
        mundane objects. To use this ability, you must have
        thieves\' tools or artisan\'s tools in hand. You then
        touch a Tiny nonmagical object as an action and
        give it one of the following magical properties of
        your choice:
        \n\t• The object sheds bright light in a 5-foot radius and
        dim light for an additional 5 feet.
        \n\t• Whenever tapped by a creature, the object emits a
        recorded message that can be heard up to 10 feet
        away. You utter the message when you bestow this
        property on the object, and the recording can be
        no more than 6 seconds long.
        \n\t• The object continuously emits your choice of an
        odor or a nonverbal sound (wind, waves, chirping,
        or the like). The chosen phenomenon is perceivable up to 10 feet away.
        \n\t• A static visual effect appears on one of the object\'s
        surfaces. This effect can be a picture, up to 25
        words of text, lines and shapes, or a mixture of
        these elements, as you like.
        \n\tThe chosen property lasts indefinitely. As an
        action, you can touch the object and end the property early.
        \n\tYou can bestow magic on multiple objects,
        touching one object each time you use this feature,
        though a single object can only bear one property
        at a time. The maximum number of objects you
        can affect with this feature at one time is equal to
        your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one object). If you try to exceed your maximum, the oldest
        property immediately ends, and then the new property applies.
        \n\n<b>THE MAGIC OF ARTIFICE</b>
        \nAs an artificer, you use tools when you cast your
        spells. When describing your spellcasting, think about
        how you\'re using a tool. For example, if you cast <i>cure
        wounds</i> using alchemist\'s supplies, you could be
        quickly producing a salve. If you cast it using tinker\'s
        tools, you might have a miniature mechanical spider
        that binds wounds. The effect of the spell is the same
        either way.
        \n\tSuch details don\'t limit you in any way or provide you
        with any benefit beyond the spell\'s effects. You don\'t
        have to justify how you\'re using tools to cast a spell.
        But describing your spellcasting creatively is a fun way
        to distinguish yourself from other spellcasters.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING</b>
        \n<i>1st-level artificer feature</i>
        \nYou\'ve studied the workings of magic and how to
        cast spells, channeling the magic through objects.
        To observers, you don\'t appear to be casting spells
        in a conventional way; you appear to produce
        wonders from mundane items and outlandish
        inventions.
        \n\n<b>TOOLS REQUIRED</b>
        \nYou produce your artificer spell effects through your
        tools. You must have a spellcasting focus - specifically
        thieves\' tools or some kind of artisan\'s tool-in
        hand when you cast any spell with this Spellcasting
        feature (meaning the spell has an "M" component
        when you cast it). You must be proficient with the
        tool to use it in this way. See the equipment chapter
        in the Player\'s Handbook for descriptions of these tools.
        \n\tAfter you gain the Infuse Item feature at 2nd level,
        you can also use any item bearing one of your infusions
        as a spellcasting focus.
        \n\n<b>CANTRIPS (0-LEVEL SPELLS)</b>
        \nYou know two cantrips of your choice from the artificer spell list.
        At higher levels, you learn additional
        artificer cantrips of your choice, as shown in the
        Cantrips Known column of the Artificer table.
        \n\tWhen you gain a level in this class, you can replace one
        of the artificer cantrips you know with
        another cantrip from the artificer spell list.
        \n\n<b>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</b>
        \n\tThe Artificer table shows how many spell slots you
        have to cast your artificer spells. To cast one of your
        artificer spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level or higher. You regain
        all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
        \n\tYou prepare the list of artificer spells that are
        available for you to cast, choosing from the artificer
        spell list. When you do so, choose a number of artificer spells equal to your Intelligence modifier + half
        your artificer level, rounded down (minimum of one
        spell). The spells must be of a level for which you
        have spell slots.
        \n\tFor example, if you are a 5th-level artificer, you
        have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots.
        With an Intelligence of 14, your list of prepared
        spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in
        any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell
        cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a
        2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn\'t remove it
        from your list of prepared spells.
        \n\tYou can change your list of prepared spells when
        you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of artificer spells
        requires time spent tinkering with your
        spellcasting focuses: at least 1 minute per spell level
        for each spell on your list.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</b>
        \n\tIntelligence is your spellcasting ability for your
        artificer spells; your understanding of the theory behind
        magic allows you to wield these spells with superior
        skill. You use your Intelligence whenever an artificer
        spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition,
        you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the
        saving throw DC for an artificer spell you cast and
        when making an attack roll with one.
        \n\t<b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier
        \n\t<b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier
        \n\n<b>RITUAL CASTING</b>
        \n\tYou can cast an artificer spell as a ritual if that spell
        has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.
        \n\n<b>INFUSE ITEM</b>
        \n<i>2nd-level artificer feature</i>
        \n\nYou\'ve gained the ability to imbue mundane items
        with certain magical infusions, turning those objects into magic items.
        \n\n<b>INFUSIONS KNOWN</b>
        \nWhen you gain this feature, pick four artificer infusions to learn,
        choosing from the "Artificer Infusions" section at the end of the class\'s description.
        You learn additional infusions of your choice when
        you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in
        the Infusions Known column of the Artificer table.
        \n\tWhenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace
        one of the artificer infusions you learned with a new one.
        \n\n<b>INFUSING ITEMS</b>
        \nWhenever you finish a long rest, you can touch a
        nonmagical object and imbue it with one of your
        artificer infusions, turning it into a magic item. An
        infusion works on only certain kinds of objects, as
        specified in the infusion\'s description. If the item requires attunement,
        you can attune yourself to it the
        instant you infuse the item. If you decide to attune to
        the item later, you must do so using the normal process for
        attunement (see the attunement rules in the <i>Dungeon Master\'s Guide</i>).
        \n\tYour infusion remains in an item indefinitely, but
        when you die, the infusion vanishes after a number
        of days equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1 day). The infusion also vanishes if you
        replace your knowledge of the infusion.
        \n\tYou can infuse more than one nonmagical object
        at the end of a long rest; the maximum number of
        objects appears in the Infused Items column of the
        Artificer table. You must touch each of the objects,
        and each of your infusions can be in only one object
        at a time. Moreover, no object can bear more than
        one of your infusions at a time. If you try to exceed
        your maximum number of infusions, the oldest infusion ends, and then the new infusion applies.
        \n\tIf an infusion ends on an item that contains other
        things, like a <i>bag of holding</i>, its contents harmlessly
        appear in and around its space.
    </string>

    <string name="bard_spellcasting_info">
        You have learned to untangle and reshape the fabric of
        reality in harmony with your wishes and music. Your
        spells are part of your vast repertoire, magic that you
        can tune to different situations.
        \n\n<b>CANTRIPS</b>
        \nYou know two cantrips of your choice from the bard
        spell list. You learn additional bard cantrips of your
        choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known
        column of the Bard table.
        \n\n<b>SPELL SLOTS</b>
        \nThe Bard table below shows how many spell slots you have to
        cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of
        these spells. you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level
        or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you
        finish a long rest.
        \n\tFor example, if you know the 1st-level spell <i>cure
        wounds</i> and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot
        available, you can cast <i>cure wounds</i> using either slot.
        \n\n<b>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</b>
        \nYou know four 1st-level spells of your choice from the
        bard spell list.
        \n\tThe Spells Known column of the Bard table shows
        when you learn more bard spells of your choice. Each of
        these spells must be of a level for which you have spell
        slots, as shown on the table. For instance, when you
        reach 3rd level in this class, you can learn one new spell
        of 1st or 2nd level.
        \n\tAdditionally, when you gain a level in this class, you
        can choose one of the bard spells you know and replace
        it with another spell from the bard spell list, which also
        must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</b>
        \nCharisma is your spellcasting ability for your bard
        spells. Your magic comes from the heart and soul you
        pour into the performance of your music or oration.
        You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your
        spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma
        modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a bard
        spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
        \n\t<b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
        \n\t<b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
        \n\n<b>RITUAL CASTING</b>
        \nYou can cast any bard spell you know as a ritual if that
        spell has the ritual tag.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</b>
        \nYou can use a musical instrument (found in chapter 5)
        as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells.
    </string>

    <string name="cleric_spellcasting_info">
        As a conduit for divine power, you can cast cleric spells.
        \n\n<b>CANTRIPS</b>
        \nAt 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from
        the cleric spell list. You learn additional cleric cantrips
        of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips
        Known column of the Cleric table.
        \n\n<b>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</b>
        \nThe Cleric table below shows how many spell slots you have
        to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of
        these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level
        or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you
        finish a long rest.
        \n\tYou prepare the list of cleric spells that are available
        for you to cast, choosing from the cleric spell list. When
        you do so, choose a number of cleric spells equal to
        your Wisdom modifier + your cleric level (minimum of
        one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you
        have spell slots.
        \n\tFor example, if you are a 3rd-level cleric, you have four
        1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom
        of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells
        of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare
        the 1st-level spell <i>cure wounds</i>, you can cast it using
        a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn\'t
        remove it from your list of prepared spells.
        \n\tYou can change your list of prepared spells when you
        finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of cleric spells
        requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1
        minute per spell level for each spell on your list.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</b>
        \nWisdom is your spellcasting ability for your cleric spells.
        The power of your spells comes from your devotion to
        your deity. You use your Wisdom whenever a cleric spell
        refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use
        your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw
        DC for a cleric spell you cast and when making an
        attack roll with one.
        \n\t<b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
        \n\t<b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
        \n\n<b>RITUAL CASTING</b>
        \nYou can cast a cleric spell as a ritual if that spell has the
        ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</b>
        \nYou can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a
        spellcasting focus for your cleric spells.
    </string>

    <string name="druid_spellcasting_info">
        Drawing on the divine essence of nature itself, you
        can cast spells to shape that essence to your will.
        \n\n<b>CANTRIPS</b>
        \nAt 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from
        the druid spell list. You learn additional druid cantrips
        of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips
        Known column of the Druid table.
        \n\n<b>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</b>
        \nThe Druid table below shows how many spell slots you have
        to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of
        these druid spells, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s
        level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when
        you finish a long rest.
        \n\tYou prepare the list of druid spells that are available
        for you to cast, choosing from the druid spell list. When
        you do so, choose a number of druid spells equal to
        your Wisdom modifier + your druid level (minimum of
        one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you
        have spell slots.
        \n\tFor example, if you are a 3rd-level druid, you have four
        1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots, With a Wisdom
        of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells
        of 1st ar 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare
        the 1st-level spell <i>cure wounds</i>, you can cast it using
        a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn\'t
        remove it from your list of prepared spells,
        \n\tYou can also change your list of prepared spells when
        you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of druid
        spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at
        least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</b>
        \nWisdom is your spellcasting ability for your druid
        spells, since your magic draws upon your devotion and
        attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever
        a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition,
        you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving
        throw DC for a druid spell you cast and when making an
        attack roll with one.
        \n\t<b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
        \n\t<b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
        \n\n<b>RITUAL CASTING</b>
        \nYou can cast a druid spell as a ritual if that spell has the
        ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</b>
        \nYou can use a druidic focus (found in chapter 5) as a
        spellcasting focus for your druid spells.
    </string>

    <string name="paladin_spellcasting_info">
        By 2nd level, you have learned to draw on divine
        magic through meditation and prayer to cast spells as
        a cleric does.
        \n\n<b>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</b>
        \nThe Paladin table below shows how many spell slots you have
        to cast your spells. To cast one of your paladin spells of
        1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s
        level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when
        you finish a long rest.
        \n\tYou prepare the list of paladin spells that are available
        for you to cast, choosing from the paladin spell list.
        When you do so, choose a number of paladin spells
        equal to your Charisma modifier + half your paladin
        level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells
        must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
        \n\tFor example, if you are a 5th-level paladin, you have
        four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a
        Charisma of 14, your list of prepared spells can include
        four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you
        prepare the 1st-level spell <i>cure wounds</i>, you can cast
        it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell
        doesn\'t remove it from your list of prepared spells.
        \n\tYou can change your list of prepared spells when you
        finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of paladin spells
        requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1
        minute per spell level for each spell on your list.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</b>
        \nCharisma is your spellcasting ability for your paladin
        spells, since their power derives from the strength of
        your convictions. You use your Charisma whenever a
        spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you
        use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving
        throw DC for a paladin spell you cast and when making
        an attack roll with one.
        \n\t<b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
        \n\t<b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</b>
        \nYou can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a
        spellcasting focus for your paladin spells.
    </string>

    <string name="ranger_spellcasting_info">
        By the time you reach 2nd level, you have learned to
        use the magical essence of nature to cast spells, much
        as a druid does.
        \n\n<b>SPELL SLOTS</b>
        \nThe Ranger table below shows how many spell slots you have
        to cast your spells of 1st and higher. To cast one of
        these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level
        or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you
        finish a long rest.
        \n\tFor example, if you know the 1st-level spell <i>animal
        friendship</i> and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot
        available, you can cast <i>animal friendship</i> using either slot.
        \n\n<b>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</b>
        \nYou know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the
        ranger spell list.
        \n\tThe Spells Known column of the Ranger table shows
        when you learn more ranger spells of your choice. Each
        of these spells must be of a level for which you have
        spell slots. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this
        class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.
        \n\tAdditionally, when you gain a level in this class,
        you can choose one of the ranger spells you know
        and replace it with another spell from the ranger
        spell list, which also must be of a level for which you
        have spell slots.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</b>
        \nWisdom is your spellcasting ability for your ranger
        spells, since your magic draws on your attunement to
        nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers
        to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your
        Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for
        a ranger spell you cast and when making an attack roll
        with one.
        \n\t<b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
        \n\t<b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
    </string>

    <string name="sorcerer_spellcasting_info">
        An event in your past, or in the life of a parent or
        ancestor, left an indelible mark on you, infusing you with
        arcane magic. This font of magic, whatever its origin,
        fuels your spells.
        \n\n<b>CANTRIPS</b>
        \nAt 1st level, you know four cantrips of your choice from
        the sorcerer spell list. You learn additional sorcerer
        cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the
        Cantrips Known column of the Sorcerer table.
        \n\n<b>SPELL SLOTS</b>
        \nThe Sorcerer table below shows how many spell slots you
        have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast
        one of these sorcerer spells, you must expend a slot of
        the spell\'s level or higher. You regain all expended spell
        slots when you finish a long rest.
        \n\tFor example, if you know the 1st-level spell <i>burning
        hands</i> and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot
        available, you can cast <i>burning hands</i> using either slot.
        \n\n<b>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</b>
        \nYou know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the
        sorcerer spell list.
        \n\tThe Spells Known column of the Sorcerer table
        shows when you learn more sorcerer spells of your
        choice. Each of these spells must be of a level for which
        you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 3rd
        level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st
        or 2nd level.
        \n\tAdditionally, when you gain a level in this class,
        you can choose one of the sorcerer spells you know
        and replace it with another spell from the sorcerer
        spell list, which also must be of a level for which you
        have spell slots.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</b>
        \nCharisma is your spellcasting ability for your sorcerer
        spells, since the power of your magic relies on your
        ability to project your will into the world. You use your
        Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting
        ability. In addition. you use your Charisma modifier
        when setting the saving throw DC for a sorcerer spell
        you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
        \n\t<b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
        \n\<b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</b>
        \nYou can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a
        spellcasting focus for your sorcerer spells.
    </string>

    <string name="warlock_spellcasting_info">
        <b>OTHERWORLDLY PATRON</b>
        \nAt 1st level, you have struck a bargain with an
        otherworldly being of your choice: the Archfey, the
        Fiend, or the Great Old One, each of which is detailed
        at the end of the class description, Your choice
        grants you features at 1st level and again at 6th, 10th,
        and 14th level.
        \n\n<b>PACT MAGIC</b>
        \nYour arcane research and the magic bestowed on you
        by your patron have given you facility with spells.
        \n\n<b>CANTRIPS</b>
        \nYou know two cantrips of your choice from the warlock
        spell list. You learn additional warlock cantrips of your
        choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known
        column of the Warlock table.
        \n\n<b>SPELL SLOTS</b>
        \nThe Warlock table below shows how many spell slots you have.
        The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all
        of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your
        warlock spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a
        spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you
        finish a short or long rest.
        \n\tFor example, when you are 5th level, you have
        two 3rd-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell
        <i>thunderwave</i>, you must spend one of those slots, and
        you cast it as a 3rd-level spell.
        \n\n<b>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</b>
        \nAt 1st level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice
        from the warlock spell list.
        \n\tThe Spells Known column of the Warlock table shows
        when you learn more warlock spells of your choice of 1st
        level and higher. A spell you choose must be of a level
        no higher than what\'s shown in the table\'s Slot Level
        column for your level. When you reach 6th level, for
        example, you learn a new warlock spell, which can be
        1st, 2nd, or 3rd level.
        \n\tAdditionally, when you gain a level in this class,
        you can choose one of the warlock spells you know
        and replace it with another spell from the warlock
        spell list, which also must be of a level for which you
        have spell slots.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</b>
        \nCharisma is your spellcasting ability for your warlock
        spells, so you use your Charisma whenever a spell refers
        lo your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your
        Charisma modifier when selling the saving throw DC
        for a warlock spell you cast and when making an attack
        roll with one.
        \n\t<b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
        \n\t<b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</b>
        \nYou can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a
        spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.
    </string>

    <string name="wizard_spellcasting_info">
        As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook
        containing spells that show the first glimmerings of
        your true power.
        \n\n<b>CANTRIPS</b>
        \nAt 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice
        from the wizard spell list. You learn additional wizard
        cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the
        Cantrips Known column of the Wizard table.
        \n\n<b>SPELLBOOK</b>
        \nAt 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level
        wizard spells of your choice.
        \n\n<b>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</b>
        \nThe Wizard table below shows how many spell slots you have
        to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of
        these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell\'s level
        or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you
        finish a long rest.
        \n\tYou prepare the list of wizard spells that are available
        for you to cast. To do so, choose a number of wizard
        spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence
        modifier + your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The
        spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
        \n\tFor example, if you\'re a 3rd-level wizard, you have
        four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With an
        Intelligence of 16, your list of prepared spells can
        include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination,
        chosen from your spellbook. If you prepare the 1st-level
        spell <i>magic missile</i>, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a
        2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn\'t remove it from
        your list of prepared spells.
        \n\tYou can change your list of prepared spells when
        you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard
        spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and
        memorizing the incantations and gestures you must
        make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level
        for each spell on your list.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</b>
        \nIntelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard
        spells, since you learn your spells through dedicated
        study and memorization. You use your Intelligence
        whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability.
        In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when
        setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast
        and when making an attack roll with one.
        \n\t<b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier
        \n\t<b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier
        \n\n<b>RITUAL CASTING</b>
        \nYou can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has
        the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook.
        You don\'t need to have the spell prepared.
        \n\n<b>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</b>
        \nYou can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting
        focus for your wizard spells.
        \n\n<b>LEARNING SPELLS OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</b>
        \nEach time you gain a wizard level, you can add two
        wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each
        of these spells must be of a level for which you have
        spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your
        adventures, you might find other spells that you can add
        to your spellbook.
        \n\n<b>YOUR SPELLBOOK</b>
        \nThe spells that you add to your spellbook as you gain levels
        reflect the arcane research you conduct on your own, as well
        as intellectual breakthroughs you have had about the nature
        of the multiverse. You might find other spells during your
        adventures. You could discover a spell recorded on a scroll in
        an evil wizard\'s chest, for example, or in a dusty tome in an
        ancient library.
        \n<i><b>Copying a Spell into the Book.</b></i> When you find a wizard spell
        of 1st level or higher, you can add it to your spellbook if it is
        of a level for which you have spell slots and if you can spare
        the time to decipher and copy it.
        \n\tCopying a spell into your spellbook involves reproducing
        the basic form of the spell, then deciphering the unique
        system of notation used by the wizard who wrote it. You
        must practice the spell until you understand the sounds
        or gestures required, then transcribe it into your spellbook
        using your own notation.
        \n\tFor each level of the spell, the process takes 2 hours and
        costs 50 gp. The cost represents material components you
        expend as you experiment with the spell to master it, as well
        as the fine inks you need to record it. Once you have spent
        this time and money, you can prepare the spell just like your
        other spells.
        \n<i><b>Replacing the Book.</b></i> You can copy a spell from your own
        spellbook into another book - for example, if you want
        to make a backup copy of your spellbook. This is just like
        copying a new spell into your spellbook, but faster and easier,
        since you understand your own notation and already know
        how to cast the spell. You need spend only 1 hour and 10 gp
        for each level of the copied spell.
        \n\tIf you lose your spellbook, you can use the same procedure
        to transcribe the spells that you have prepared into a new
        spellbook. Filling out the remainder of your spellbook
        requires you to find new spells to do so, as normal. For this
        reason, many wizards keep backup spellbooks in a safe place.
        \n<i><b>The Book\'s Appearance.</b></i> Your spellbook is a unique
        compilation of spells, with its own decorative flourishes and
        margin notes. It might be a plain, functional leather volume
        that you received as a gift from your master, a finely bound
        gilt-edged tome you found in an ancient library, or even a
        loose collection of notes scrounged together after you lost
        your previous spellbook in a mishap.
    </string>

</resources>